Shruti Dhange

7 months experience as a Data Science Intern. 1+ year overall experience in Data Science including internship and rigorous assignments and capstone projects at LJM University. Data Scientist with a passion for delivering valuable insights through analytical functions and data retrieval methods.

shrutidhange@gmail.com

+91 8329760739

kaggle_{https://www.kaggle.com/shrutidhange}

https://github.com/shrutidhange

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/shruti-dhange/

EDUCATION

Liverpool John Moores University— M.S. in Data Science

Aug 2022 - Feb 2024

Statistics, Predictive Analytics using Python, Machine Learning, Data Visualization, Big Data Analytics, Deep Learning.

International Institute of Information Technology, Bangalore (IIIT-B), — Executive PG Programme in Data Science

Aug 2022 - Aug 2023

Statistics, Predictive Analytics using Python, Machine Learning, Data Visualization, Big Data Analytics, Deep Learning.

SINHGAD INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, LONAVALA, PUNE — B.E. in Mechanical Engineering

Jun 2009 - Jun 2013

EXPERIENCE

CodeClause, Bangalore — Data Science Intern

Aug 2023 - Sep 2023

Developed machine learning models for predicting loan approvals and speech emotion, contributing to real-world problem-solving in financial and audio data domains.

Conducted data preprocessing, feature engineering, and model selection, enhancing accuracy and effectiveness of predictive models.

Utilized Python and libraries such as scikit-learn and TensorFlow to implement classification algorithms and regression techniques.

Gained hands-on experience in handling imbalanced datasets, optimizing model parameters, and extracting meaningful insights from data.

iNeuron AI, Bangalore — Data Science Intern

Feb 2023 - Sep 2023

Predictive maintenance, hands-on experience in prognostics and health management.

COURSES

Hadoop Foundation Level 1 (Hadoop 101) (IBM) Sep 2023

Deep Learning - ML2 (IIIT-B) Jul 2023

Machine Learning -ML1 (IIIT-B) Jul 2023

Data Toolkit (IIIT-B) Mar 2023

Data Science Programming Bootcamp (UpGrad) Sep, 2022

SKILLS

Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning, Regression, Classification, Clustering

Strong analytical and communication skill

Big Data, Hadoop, Spark, Spark ML

Tableau, PowerBI,

Working with run-to-failure simulation data from turbofan jet engines, I utilized the data provided by The Prognostics CoE at NASA Ames. My main objective was to predict the remaining useful life (RUL) of each engine, representing the number of flights left after the last data point in the test dataset. This internship allowed me to explore the crucial role of predictive maintenance in anticipating asset states and avoiding downtime and breakdowns in industrial settings.

Megha Automation and Robotics Pvt. Ltd, Pune — Design Engineer

Aug 2013 - Sep 2014

Utilized Pro-e and AutoCAD to design a boiler jacket. This involved creating detailed 3D models and technical drawings to ensure accurate specifications and efficient manufacturing processes

Project Work

Melanoma Detection - multiclass classification model using a custom convolutional neural network in TensorFlow

Mar 2023 - Jun 2023

To build a CNN based model which can accurately detect melanoma. Melanoma is a type of cancer that can be deadly if not detected early. It accounts for 75% of skin cancer deaths. A solution that can evaluate images and alert dermatologists about the presence of melanoma has the potential to reduce a lot of manual effort needed in diagnosis.

Customer Churn Prediction

lan 2023 - Feb 2023

Machine learning classification model to predict which customers are at high risk of churn.

Credit Risk Analysis

Sep 2022 - Oct 2022

Risk analytics in banking and financial services and understand how data is used to minimize the risk of losing money while lending to customers.

Prediction of demand for Bike Sharing application

Dec 2022 - Jan 2023

Multiple linear regression model for the prediction of demand for shared bikes, feature selection using Recursive Feature Elimination, sk learn regression modeling, model evaluation.

Used by the management to understand how exactly the demands vary with different features. They can accordingly manipulate the business strategy to meet the demand levels and meet the customer's expectations. Further, the model will be a good way for management to understand the demand dynamics of a new market

Advanced SQL

Python, Sci-kit learn, PyTorch, TensorFlow

Matplotlib, Seaborn

Data Analysis

Data Cleaning,
Exploratory Data
Analysis, Feature
Engineering, Feature
Selection, Model
Building, Model
Evaluation,
Hyperparameter
Tuning, Model
Evaluation, Cross
Validation

Predictive Modeling

Deep Neural Network,Deep Learning,Convolution Neural Network, Recurrent Neural Network, LSTM, GRU,

HOBBIES

Table Tennis, Badminton, Painting, Cooking, Learning

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Marathi, Kannada

ADDRESS

Flat No 1009, BREN Starlight, Avalahalli, Cheemasandra Gate, On Old Madras Road, Bangalore - 560049